<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: social | James Michiemo]]></title>
  <link href="http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/blog/categories/social/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-10T19:34:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[James Michiemo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Solavei]]></title>
    <link href="http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/blog/2013/03/25/introducing-solavei/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-25T15:14:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/blog/2013/03/25/introducing-solavei</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.funinoklahoma.com/1-%20Global/Solavei/Pics,%20Logos,%20Flyers/Solavei_Logo_4c_notag_600.png" alt="Solavei" /></p>

<p>A few months ago, I learned about a new mobile service called <a href="http://www.solavei.com/omeichim">Solavei</a>. Back then I was looking around for a reasonable unlimited phone plan that didn&rsquo;t involve contracts. At the time, my phone carrier was <a href="http://goredpocket.com">Red Pocket Mobile</a>, which was great but their mobile web data plan costed more and was limited to only 2gigs of data and I wasn&rsquo;t going to sign a contract with another mobile service to be charged for more data usage.</p>

<p>Personally, I can&rsquo;t stand contract service agreements. If I&rsquo;m unhappy with anyone&rsquo;s service, I should be able to decide not to continue doing business with them. Why should I guarantee my money every month to a phone service that&rsquo;s questionable? I&rsquo;ve always felt more comfortable using a prepaid plan. I like the freedom of having other options available.</p>

<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t really trust them at first since they&rsquo;re a completely new company, but my family in Dallas who I love and trust assured me that Solavei was something that I would want to be a part of.</p>

<p>After hours of research, I went ahead and ditched my old plan and ordered my unlimited phone plan with <a href="http://www.solavei.com/omeichim">Solavei</a>. It&rsquo;s been 3 months already and I&rsquo;m 100% satisfied with their revolutionary phone service.</p>

<p>My prepaid plan came up to $58.34 a month including tax and that&rsquo;s without participating in their <a href="http://www.solavei.com/what-is-solavei">referral program</a>. If you recruit enough members to Solavei, eventually, you won&rsquo;t even have a monthly bill to pay. Solavei actually pays its members for sharing their services with other people.</p>

<p>Switching carriers was a no brainer for me. There were no activation fees involved other than the 9 dollar SIM card I had to ship to myself. Once I got my SIM card in the mail, I popped it into my iPhone and I was set. I&rsquo;ve never been happier with my phone.</p>

<p>It feels awesome to be able to blog about this new service as an early adopter. I have a feeling that Solavei is only going to get bigger. Be sure to check out Solavie&rsquo;s video down below to learn more.</p>

<div class="video-container">
    <iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Jcg-9YCx3Gg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>      
</div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
