<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tips | James Michiemo]]></title>
  <link href="http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/blog/categories/tips/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-24T23:27:19-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[James Michiemo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing ChucK on Ubuntu]]></title>
    <link href="http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/blog/2013/10/24/installing-chuck-on-ubuntu/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-24T16:12:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/blog/2013/10/24/installing-chuck-on-ubuntu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately, I&rsquo;ve been getting into this thing called &ldquo;live coding&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s an improvisational programming technique used to orchestrate light and sound. I&rsquo;ve watched a few demos of it and I&rsquo;m already hooked on the idea of learning how to do this sort of thing. Currently, I&rsquo;m taking a couple of classes to become better at programming, so I feel like it&rsquo;s the perfect thing to play around with for fun.</p>

<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://jamesmichiemo.github.io//www.youtube.com/embed/GSGKEy8vHqg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m using the ChucK programming language to get a feel for making music with algorithms. It&rsquo;s a language made specifically for manipulating sound and it&rsquo;s fun to play with, but what wasn&rsquo;t fun was figuring out how to install it on Ubuntu.</p>

<p>I had no problems installing with Mac, but the Ubuntu installation was a bit more involved. I tried the old ./configure, make, make install trick on the source file but I was missing too many dependencies for it to run. I then checked for an apt-get package but then chuck told me that I was missing an audio API to connect to so I was stuck with a music programming language that couldn&rsquo;t make a sound.</p>

<p>After searching through message boards, mailing lists, and blogs, I was able to find a solution from a post about <a href="http://t-a-w.blogspot.com/2007/05/using-ddr-dance-mat-as-musical.html">&ldquo;Using a DDR dance mat as a musical instrument&rdquo;</a>. Not my intention, but cool idea.</p>

<p>The author had figured out that you need to run apt-get chuck with another application call jackd. First you need to run the installation:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo apt-get install chuck jackd</code></pre>


<p>ChucK still won&rsquo;t work since you need jackd running at the same time, so once you have jackd installed, go ahead and run this in a new terminal:</p>

<pre><code>$ jackd -d alsa</code></pre>


<p>Leave that terminal running in the background somewhere and then proceed to run ChucK with this line:</p>

<pre><code>$ chuck --srate48000 *.ck</code></pre>


<p></p>

<p>And that should be it. After running that last line I was able to hear some audio from my speakers.</p>

<p>If you have a Mac, rejoice. It&rsquo;s only one click. FML</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Damage Control]]></title>
    <link href="http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/damage-control/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-18T18:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/damage-control</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My Macbook is dead. I knew this would happen one day, especially at an important time, like now, when I&rsquo;m preparing for an internship interview for Linkedin. It&rsquo;s entirely my fault. I shouldn&rsquo;t have been drinking and typing. It was a sad moment to watch the water from my cup flow right through my keyboard buttons, but it wasn&rsquo;t as painful as it could have been.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Djnih.gif" alt="sad face" /></p>

<p>Right now, I&rsquo;m looking into getting my Macbook replaced but in the meantime I have work to do. Luckily, I&rsquo;ve got another machine at home running Ubuntu. Right before my disaster, I was able to upload my dotfile configurations to Github, so I&rsquo;m fortunate enough to be able to transfer my previous development environment over to my Ubuntu laptop. It&rsquo;s an old and clunky laptop compared to my Macbook but it works almost completely the same as far as Unix tools.</p>

<p>I also dodged a bullet by keeping all my current projects on Dropbox. I&rsquo;d have to say that Dropbox probably uses up the most processing power out of all the applications on my machine right now but it&rsquo;s worth it having all your important documents synced just in case anything happens. Backing up files is never a bad idea.</p>

<p>I should be more upset about my situation but everything happens for a reason. I&rsquo;ll just remember this as a learning experience and a lesson in how you can never be too prepared for when disaster strikes.</p>

<p>Back up everything.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
