<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rails | James Michiemo]]></title>
  <link href="http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/blog/categories/rails/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-27T03:03:24-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[James Michiemo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dev Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/blog/2013/02/17/devboot/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-17T12:34:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jamesmichiemo.github.io/blog/2013/02/17/devboot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ahhh! Right now I am super nervous about my <a href="http://Skype.com">Skype</a> interview with <a href="http://devbootcamp.com">Dev Bootcamp</a> coming up in a few days. It&rsquo;s a bit intimidating considering their low acceptance rate for applicants.</p>

<p><img src="http://scm-l3.technorati.com/12/12/13/73853/devbootcamp.png?t=20121213131231" alt="Dev Bootcamp logo" /></p>

<p><a href="http://devbootcamp.com">Dev Bootcamp</a> is an intense 9 week training workshop located in San Francisco and Chicago. They take both beginner and experienced programmers, turning them into readily employable <a href="http://rubyonrails.org">Rails</a> beasts.</p>

<p>I first found out about DBC from reading a few discussions about the program on <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/news">Hacker News</a> and I was impressed with what they had to offer in their curriculum. They cover mainly <a href="http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/">Ruby</a>, <a href="http://rubyonrails.com">Rails</a>, <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/JavaScript">JavaScript</a>, and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agile_software_development">Agile</a> methodologies. It&rsquo;s very similar to what I&rsquo;m learning in <a href="http://www.fullsail.edu/degrees/campus/web-design-development-bachelors">Full Sail&rsquo;s web program</a> so I&rsquo;m sure I&rsquo;ll be prepared once I start my training at DBC.</p>

<p>To handle my nerves, I&rsquo;ve been pushing myself much harder to learn how to become a Rails developer. My classes at Full Sail University have been a huge help so far and the tips that I&rsquo;ve gotten from meetups with <a href="http://teamtreehouse.com">Team Treehouse</a> and <a href="http://www.codeschool.com">Code School</a> have been inspiring for me.</p>

<p>I know this career field is a good fit for me, but I still have my doubts about whether I&rsquo;ll be able to get into Dev Bootcamp. I&rsquo;m not the best student at school and I barely have enough experience with code to impress anyone familiar with dev subject matter. Right now, I&rsquo;m just relying on my passion to learn.</p>

<p>All I know for sure is that my path to becoming a Rails developer is going to be long and challenging, but I&rsquo;ll enjoy writing every step of the way.</p>

<p>Wish me luck!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
